# 江苏·扬州
Yangzhou, Jiangsu
# 这来到刚卖完一炉 我们还需要等一下
They just sold out, we need to wait
# 它这个（金刚蹄）是什么面做的（烫面、发面、死面）
What is it (Jin'gangti) made of (dough made with boiling water, leavened dough or unleavened dough)?
# 闻着有一种发酵的味道
It smells like fermented
# 这是老面肥（上次发酵剩的面）做面引子
This is the old dough fertilizer (the leftover from the last fermentation dough)
# 等到面涨起来之后 兑碱 放食用碱
After the dough rise up, add alkali and edible alkali
# 放在里面 进行酸碱中和 面涨起来 它会酸
Put it in the dough for acid-base neutralization
# 酸然后放碱 进行酸碱中和
Acid then add alkali for acid-base neutralization
# 就是说 这个面要涨得好 碱要兑得好
In other words, the alkali must be well mixed so the dough will rise well
# 东西才能好
Food can be good
# 刚才有句话没录上
There was a sentence that was not recorded
# 他说 做金刚蹄 最重要的是什么
He said, what's the most important to make Jingangti
# 最重要的是 面发得好
The most important is the dough rise good
# 不能酸了 也不能说 发酵的不够
It can’t be too sour, it can’t be not fermented enough
# 还有一点就是 他们为了做出这种形状
And they in order to make this shape
# 在面上 切三下
Cut three time on the dough
# 这样才能出现六角铮铮的样子
So it looks like a hexagonal
# 金刚蹄是什么口味的 甜的还是咸的
What’s the flavor of Jingangti? Sweet or salty?
# 甜的 现在更多一点 但是也有人要吃咸的
More sweet now, but someone like salty
# 它这个是扬州本地的特色吗
Is this a local street food of Yangzhou?
# 差不多吧 现在只有扬州才有了
Sort of, only in yangzhou now
# 以前 江苏 上海 浙江都有的 江浙沪都有的
In the past, it had in Jiangsu, Shanghai, Zhejiang,
# 在扬州本地 它是不叫金刚蹄的 是吧
It is not called jingangti in the local right?
# 就叫刚蹄子 金刚蹄也叫刚蹄子
It is called gangtizi
# 上海人 叫它老虎爪
Shanghai people called it tiger claw
# 您做这个做多久了
How long have you been doing this?
# 我做这个 做30多年了
More than 30 years
# 做了一辈子了
Do it for my lifetime
# 我站老半天 才发现 之前的炉子是有炭放进去的
I stood there for a long time and just find out that there was charcoal in the stove
# 在金刚蹄放进去之前呢 要把炭火拿出来
He need to take the charcoal before put Jingangti in
# 然后用清水给炉子降降温 这个时候呢 才把面团贴到炉子里
Then use water to cool down the stove. and stick the dough on the stove.
# 做金刚蹄呢 炉子的温度太高 手插不进去
For making Jingangti, You can not put hand in if the temperature of the stove is too high
# 太低呢 贴在炉壁上是贴不住的
And dough is hard to stick on the stove wall if the temperature is too low
# 所以 这个温度是很重要的
So the temperature is very important
# 开始准备撒糖了
It’s time to pour sugar on the top
# 把糖罐子烧红之后 把糖放进去
After burning the sugar jar to red, put the sugar in
# 老板 还得多长时间  大概5分钟就可以出炉了
How long will it take? About five minutes
# 顾客：反正我钱付了 明天这个时候过来拿
Customer: Anyway, I paid. And i will come and get it at this time tomorrow
# 刚出炉的金刚蹄 确实是很像老虎的爪子
The freshly baked Jingangti are indeed like tiger claws
# 像老虎爪子 也像一朵比较饱满的花
Also looks like a fuller flower
# 这是我等了好几炉 才拿到的金刚蹄
This is the Jingangti that I waited for several stoves to get
# 它一共有6个花瓣 看上去特别漂亮
It has a total of 6 petals and looks very beautiful
# 我真的是忍不住想吃一口
I can’t wait to give a bite
# 很像面包
Looks like bread
# 它这个是微微甜 还能吃出这种面的发酵的味道
It taste slightly sweet and it can taste the fermented taste of dough
# 上面呢 就是这个瓣的地方 特别柔软 松软
The upper part is the place where this flap is very soft
# 其实 你仔细按压一下
Actually if you press it carefully
# 也会发现 它是有很大的孔隙的
You will find out that it has large pores
# 下面接触炉壁的地方 就会变得很脆
The blow area which close to the stove wall will become
# 尤其是刚出炉的时候 变得特别酥脆 可口
Especially when it is fresh baked, it get very crispy and delicious
# 它有个好处就是吃起来没有那么甜
It has an advantage that it tastes not so sweet
# 这是脆的
It is crispy
# 它这边的金刚蹄是分咸的和甜的
They have sweet and salty Jingangti
# 但是说咸的卖的比较少 一般都是甜的
But customer usually buy sweet mostly
# 走近 靠近金刚蹄的时候 你会觉得
When you walk in and get close to fresh baked Jingangti
# 面香味浓郁 尤其加上烤制 这个味道就是更加吸引人
The dough have a strong flavor, especially when roasted, the taste is even more attractive
# 我感觉它就像一个烤面包 一个1块5
It feels like a baked bread, 1.5 yuan for each
# 其实这个价格还是很可以的 比较平价了
Actually, the price is quite reasonable
# 为什么说 我是等了好几炉才买上
The reason i waited for several stoves to get is
# 因为在我前面 每一炉做好都有一个人会要几十个
Because every customers in front of me who always order dozens of Jinggangti after a stove of fresh baked Jinggangti out
# 我前一炉 那个是要了20个
One guy purchased 20 when the previous stove was baked
# 前前炉 也有一个人要了很多个带走的
Similar things happened one stove before.
# 所以呢 我就等了3炉才等到这5个金刚蹄
So i wait 3 stove for 5 jingangti
# 吃完 走
I’m done, lets go
# 关 注
# 雪 鱼 探 店
Subscribe xueyu